Welcome back to Am Northwest. Well, we
always learn interesting facts from our
next guest here to share a poster art
collection. We welcome back antique
appraiser Gary Germer. Great to see
you. >> me back. >> Okay, so this client
has an amazing collection here.
And tell me how he or she came in.
Well, he first of all [clears throat]
called me and and he's wanting to
downsize. >> Yeah. And he said he had a
few posters and when I went there he had
a little over 2,000. >> Oh my gosh. Wow.
>> take 2,000 at the moment so we're
doing them in segments. And so then I've
learned I just love them. I just love
the colors. I love the different reasons
people collect them. You know. And some
of these are really valuable. >> Some
can be. >> Yeah. Now, you when we were
kids you got went down to the mall and
bought a poster or if you had a friend
who worked at the movie theater they would
give you the poster of the movie that
just ended and whatnot. Some of those
are even becoming somewhat valuable.
>> Oh, wow. But there's different categories
people do. On the end here >> This
one?
Yeah. This this one You
looking at this one? Yeah.
That's probably one of the hottest
subjects right now are old TRAVEL POSTERS.
>> OH, THEY LOOK really cool. >> Mid-century
modern home Mhm. having the colors
the bright colors and the the the travel
and things like that as well as things
like this which is uh bright colored
posters. When you're looking if you want to
be a collector or looking to see if
you have something that is collectible.
There we go. uh What you want to look
at is is it have colors that pop, you
know. Is it something that you really
like? That's what you want to buy any art
for is that you you it's something that
you like. But this one here for example
is an old rock and roll poster advertising
that old poster up in Seattle and
it was from the 1980s and >> So how
much does something like that go for if
you're selling it? >> like that is
about maybe in the $150 to $200 range.
>> Okay. The travel poster is closer to
$800. Oh, wow. It's 1960s and stuff like
that. >> Yeah. I love them. People buy
this one here. I'll lift this one up.
>> If you can lift that one up. For
example, those are from art galleries. And
these were advertised. And the thing about
a poster is they were always meant to
be I don't know. Let's Let's slide it
right over on top of that and then I can
see it. >> I'm sorry I brought the largest
things in the shop. That's all right.
Um You have for our poster, the bottom
one is a Decrouning um uh gallery
show in Seattle they had back in '86.
And what's cool about that one is he
signed it. >> Yeah. >> And so
that makes it even more valuable.
>> And >> And it's in great condition,
too. >> Yeah. And uh Amazing. >> that.
Yeah. And so of course
like I said, they were meant to be posters
originally were the original social
media. They didn't have They didn't have
you know, we have the internet. So they
wanted something to grab your eye that
would be for a temporary use only. Glued
onto the side of the walls or, you know,
thrown away at the end. So that's why
they're more scarce and valuable now,
especially in really good condition.
>> Okay. And how do you sell them? Do you
sell them online usually? Cuz it's not
like It's not like you're having an
estate sale, is it? >> we sell through our
website. We have a We have an online
These this this this collection and a lot
of the stuff that I bring we have
available on our website. >> Okay. Um this
here and the one behind it, the Chinese
girl behind it, would be used for
advertising stores. This one in
front is a famous one from 1904.
Wow. >> And what they were It's kind
of a um What do they call it? Fake full
medicine thing. The guy's holding this
cotton product that was chemically
treated you were supposed to put under
your clothes to keep you warm in the
winter. That's why flames are coming out
of his mouth. It was a French idea in
the early 20th century. >>
Oh, leave it to the French.
>> Yeah. I love it. You know, you talk
about color cuz you know I love color. I
just think that even just for the color
and then the look of the French looks
really cool. >> Isn't it fun? I just
think it's really great. >> Yeah. I think
that and this one here is uh
from a Chinese grocery store. No
way. How beautiful is that? Yeah.
From about the length well before the
war. So it would have been 1930s so it was
done. >> And she's a pretty girl and
they were but it's surprisingly only a
couple hundred dollars, you know, if you
wanted to go with that sort of thing.
>> I love the art to it. The I mean
that's what we're talking about is art.
Right. And that's it. And it's a type
of art that's dis- was disposable.
The what makes them rare and what makes
them valuable First of all, what makes
them valuable is how rare are they? Who
designed them? The colors and and you
know, like the travel posters just right
in right now as far as design goes.
Condition is part of it, but like this
particular poster and if we can look at
one is a lot of times old ones, I'm telling
an old one. They come folded. And so
being folded is not a problem. That's
actually an indication that it's older.
The paper's going to be thin and one of
the things will happen over the years is
this will break and this is a actually
an incredibly famous poster. And they'll
have issues like there's tape on this
one. This could be restored and restoring
posters
actually adds to their value if they're
professionally Usually on something like
this what they'll do is put it on linen
backing so it's a heavy backing to in
order to keep it from you know, deteriorating
further and you can frame it and
it goes on and that's actually very
acceptable in in the um You You pointed to
that one right there. So can we Yep.
Tell me about that. Those are These were
the war posters. I'm going to step over
here. Yeah. Um this one here is like
this one. You can tell in looking at
it that it's been folded. World War I
uh poster here for whatever reason they
didn't have enough books. It's books
wanted for our men and for their
over uh for the guys over there.
And so an early doughboy one, it has
some issues has a little bit of tear here
that somebody tried to fix it one
time. But again, this could be restored
beautifully. >> Yeah. Uh World War guys
historians tend to collect people who
collect history tend to collect by wars
and things like that. So then this one
here on the bottom down here is from
World War II. Oh, wow. And I love the
graphics on that and that's what
was to get everybody enthused about
um you know, about you know, buying bonds
and getting the war done and so that
we could and so there was a lot of
posters of that vein. And so for World War
collectors, that's an exciting poster and
that's that's about a thousand dollars
for that. >> Oh, really? Okay. And then
just to This one. be controversial for
anybody watching. This is actually from
North Vietnam. This is a propaganda
poster from Vietnam after they won the
war. They they're claiming they won the
war. They brought peace. Communism brought
peace and there's a US B-52 crashed
in the background. >> Wow. And so you
don't see that very often. I had to say
that. That that's what the other side
was telling their people. >> Yeah. And so
again, historians Vietnam War era people
political of different spectrums love
to have stuff like that. How do you let's
say someone buys one of these like how
do you mail them even?
Well, you can and I'm
roll them carefully in a large tube. >>
Okay. >> So that they can be unfolded.
Part of the problem you have and I
have a whole bunch of these back at the
office is they've been tightly Wow.
>> And so then you got to worry about
flattening them. Yeah. Oh my gosh.
Incredible Gary Germer. Incredible stuff. All
right, we'll be right back with
more AM Northwest. Don't go away.